<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scipy on Stéfan&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://mentat.za.net/blog/tags/scipy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scipy on Stéfan&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mentat.za.net/blog/tags/scipy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Python at Microscopy &amp; MicroAnalysis 2019</title>
      <link>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2019/08/06/portland-microscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2019/08/06/portland-microscopy/</guid>
      <description>Today, I presented a talk titled &amp;ldquo;Scientific Python: A Mature Computational Ecosystem for Microscopy&amp;rdquo; [PDF] at the Microscopy and MicroAnalysis conference in Portland.
A few members of the audience familiar with scientific Python told me they had learned something, so I&amp;rsquo;ll highlight the few topics that I think may have qualified.
SciPy 1.0 paper The first official release of SciPy was in 2001, and a mere 16 years later we reached 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SciPy2013 Proceedings</title>
      <link>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2013/06/27/scipy2013-proceedings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2013/06/27/scipy2013-proceedings/</guid>
      <description>The talks for the 12th (fantastic) Python in Science conference just concluded, and I am happy to announce the conference proceedings.
This may come as a surprize to some, since in the past we have been unable to publish the proceedings in a timely manner. So, what changed?
Review process For 2013 we followed a very light-weight review process, via comments on GitHub pull-requests. This change has an important consequence: in contrast to the traditional review process, where reviewers critically pull apart papers, the process now changes into a constructive conversation&amp;ndash;the reviewer becomes an ally to the author, helping them to get their paper signed off on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scikits-image 0.7</title>
      <link>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2012/09/30/scikits-image-0-dot-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2012/09/30/scikits-image-0-dot-7/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce the 7th version of scikits-image!
Scikits-image is an image processing toolbox for SciPy that includes algorithms for segmentation, geometric transformations, color space manipulation, analysis, filtering, morphology, feature detection, and more.
For more information, examples, and documentation, please visit our website.
New Features It&amp;rsquo;s been only 3 months since scikits-image 0.6 was released, but in that short time, we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to add plenty of new features and enhancements, including</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs package management</title>
      <link>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2012/09/25/emacs-package-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2012/09/25/emacs-package-management/</guid>
      <description>I recently tried to install MuMaMo as one of the dependencies for Takafumi Arakaki&amp;rsquo;s Emacs-based IPython notebook. The instructions on the MuMaMo webpage were as clear as mud and aimed primarily at Windows users. Enters apt-get for Emacs!
My Emacs setup is shared across multiple machines: a synchronized elisp folder, containing *.el files, along with my .emacs configuration. el-get allows you to share your package installation folder in a similar fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>