<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>science on Stéfan&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://mentat.za.net/blog/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in science on Stéfan&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mentat.za.net/blog/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write Good Scientific Software</title>
      <link>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2020/08/19/how-to-write-good-scientific-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2020/08/19/how-to-write-good-scientific-software/</guid>
      <description>This is a lightly edited transcript of a talk I delivered at MLSS South Africa on 16 January 2019.
In this post, I will define scientific software, describe how it is different from other types of software, and discuss the social, mechanical, and scholarly disciplines required for making it the best it can be.
Upfront, I should note that these are all rough guidelines, but that the context in which software is developed and used will affect the extent to which they apply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replicable super-resolution paper</title>
      <link>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2012/10/15/replicable-super-resolution-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2012/10/15/replicable-super-resolution-paper/</guid>
      <description>While I loved the topic of my PhD, I had to take a break after staring at that problem for several years. Thereafter, I was side-tracked by several other projects, and never got around to publishing a paper on my dissertation.
Here, then, is a summary of the simple but effective super-resolution algorithm described therein:
http://arxiv.org/abs/1210.3404
I also submitted this work to NIPS: the reviewers liked the paper, but they were not convinced of its novelty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scikits-image 0.7</title>
      <link>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2012/09/30/scikits-image-0-dot-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mentat.za.net/blog/2012/09/30/scikits-image-0-dot-7/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce the 7th version of scikits-image!
Scikits-image is an image processing toolbox for SciPy that includes algorithms for segmentation, geometric transformations, color space manipulation, analysis, filtering, morphology, feature detection, and more.
For more information, examples, and documentation, please visit our website.
New Features It&amp;rsquo;s been only 3 months since scikits-image 0.6 was released, but in that short time, we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to add plenty of new features and enhancements, including</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>