<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Stéfan van der Walt - drm amazon kindle ebooks</title><link href="http://mentat.za.net/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mentat.za.net/blog/feeds/tag_drm-amazon-kindle-ebooks.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mentat.za.net/blog/</id><updated>2016-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Amazon owns your ebooks</title><link href="http://mentat.za.net/blog/2016/08/21/amazon-owns-your-ebooks/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Stefan van der Walt</name></author><id>tag:mentat.za.net,2016-08-21:/blog/2016/08/21/amazon-owns-your-ebooks/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Did you know that Amazon does not sell ebooks?  But, wait, you say, I
have bought ebooks from them myself!  Sadly, that is not the case.  I
will summarize part of the
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201014950"&gt;Kindle Store Terms of Use&lt;/a&gt;
quoted at the bottom of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You do not own any Kindle …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Did you know that Amazon does not sell ebooks?  But, wait, you say, I
have bought ebooks from them myself!  Sadly, that is not the case.  I
will summarize part of the
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201014950"&gt;Kindle Store Terms of Use&lt;/a&gt;
quoted at the bottom of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You do not own any Kindle book that you have "bought", even if it
   said "buy with one click" in the store (the book still belongs to
   Amazon, you're just leasing it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may only read Kindle content through sofware approved by
   Amazon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may not copy ebooks "bought" from Amazon to other devices (such
   as a Kobo or Nook reader).  In fact, you may not engage in any
   activity that bypasses their Digital Rights Management (or DRM).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;s&gt;bought&lt;/s&gt; rent more than 120 Kindle books, and to my shame
only realized the invasive nature of these terms now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since your agreement with Amazon is simply a license to view material,
they have the ability to withdraw that right whenever they choose.
&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/07/18/technology/companies/18amazon.html"&gt;Which they have done, in an ironic twist, with George Orwell's 1984&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may imagine, this whole situation riles me up quite badly, and
spoils many a dinner-time conversation (sorry, friends).  I am
particularly irate because I just bought myself a beautiful
&lt;a href="http://www.cnet.com/products/kobo-glo-hd/"&gt;Kobo Glo HD&lt;/a&gt;, in a slow
but measured move to lessen my dependence on Amazon.  Now, lo and
behold, I cannot access any of the 120 books which, if I gave my money
to other ebook stores, I would have owned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;em&gt;caveat emptor&lt;/em&gt;, dear reader.  &lt;strong&gt;Do not support Amazon's great
&lt;a href="https://www.defectivebydesign.org/amazon-kindle-swindle"&gt;Kindle Swindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you buy books from Kobo, you will be able to export your books to
your Kindle devices, albeit encumbered by Digital Rights Management (DRM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The deal with Digital Rights Management (DRM)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this post is about Amazon Kindle, it is worth mentioning Digital
Rights Management (DRM).  DRM is a mechanism that distributers use to
lock their books so that you may not easily copy it illegally.  Of
course, and very predictably, the DRM is not difficult to circumvent,
and those who want to steal electronic books do so with impunity.
Still, it is
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anti-circumvention#Fair_Use_and_Circumvention"&gt;probably illegal to remove DRM in the United States&lt;/a&gt;,
and if you're a law abiding citizen, you cannot convert a protected
ebook to another format such as PDF, even if a PDF would be more
convenient for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some distributors are worse than others, though, and unsurprisingly
Amazon is one of the worst.  Not only do they lock their books (making
it difficult to copy to other devices), but they use a proprietary
format (.mobi) that only works on &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; readers.  If you want to
copy their books to another device, you &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to first remove the DRM
which, as their terms state, is not allowed.  You might start to
wonder whether such business practices aren't anti-competitive and
perhaps even illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a perfectly usable format for ebooks already in existence
(.epub), that is also supported by many different models of readers.
So, while locking books with some kind of DRM is far from ideal, it is
still preferable to using a proprietary format to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those buying from the Kobo store, some of the books on their
shelves are available DRM-free, and is indicated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Kobo DRM information" src="http://mentat.za.net/blog/images/kobo_drm_comparison.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defective by Design maintains a
&lt;a href="https://www.defectivebydesign.org/guide/ebooks"&gt;list of DRM-free publishers and stores&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://www.defectivebydesign.org/action"&gt;support&lt;/a&gt; the
&lt;a href="http://eff.org"&gt;Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, who is currently
&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/jul/21/digital-millennium-copyright-act-eff-supreme-court"&gt;challenging DMCA Section 1201&lt;/a&gt;
(which makes it illegal to circumvent DRM).  There is no good reason
why you should not be allowed to read material you bought on any
device of your choosing.  For more on the DRM, refer to author
&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/blog/2014/feb/05/digital-rights-management"&gt;Cory Doctorow's articles in the Guardian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below follows an excerpt, mentioned above, from the Amazon Kindle
Store's Terms of Use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Kindle Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Kindle Content.&lt;/strong&gt; Upon your download of Kindle Content and
payment of any applicable fees (including applicable taxes), the
Content Provider grants you a non-exclusive right to view, use, and
display such Kindle Content an unlimited number of times, solely
through a Reading Application or as otherwise permitted as part of
the Service, solely on the number of Supported Devices specified in
the Kindle Store, and solely for your personal, non-commercial
use. Kindle Content is licensed, not sold, to you by the Content
Provider. The Content Provider may include additional terms for use
within its Kindle Content. Those terms will also apply, but this
Agreement will govern in the event of a conflict. Some Kindle
Content, such as interactive or highly formatted content, may not be
available to you on all Reading Applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limitations.&lt;/strong&gt; Unless specifically indicated otherwise, you may
not sell, rent, lease, distribute, broadcast, sublicense, or
otherwise assign any rights to the Kindle Content or any portion of
it to any third party, and you may not remove or modify any
proprietary notices or labels on the Kindle Content. In addition,
you may not attempt to bypass, modify, defeat, or otherwise
circumvent any digital rights management system or other content
protection or features used as part of the Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="drm amazon kindle ebooks"></category></entry></feed>